[Music]
welcome to this session where uh we
introduce a new way of interacting with
your data with Microsoft co-pilot
through chat uh and we'll talk a little
bit about how this will be
transformative for your uh business
processes I'm Sam van lout I'm a
software engineer at Microsoft and I'm
joined here with my colleague Mike hi
Mike thanks Sam my name is Mike borch
cardana and I'm a product manager at
Microsoft so uh we're excited to
announce uh the ability to chat with
Microsoft co-pilot within Dynamics 365
business Central uh will enter public
preview in 2024 release Wave 1 uh so
co-pilot is the the AI powered assistant
that empowers people to express
themselves in their own words uh to find
records as well as enabling uh people to
easily get answers to questions on how
when or why to do um things within uh
business Central so why have we gone
ahead and integrated uh chat with
business Central um we know that
sometimes business apps can be uh quite
hard to learn and uh chat opens up a
whole new way to interact with your data
uh making the business apps a lot more
approachable and uh accessible to
people um along uh with that uh business
Central has a growing uh set of uh uh
diverse customers um and chat is an
opportunity for copat to assist with the
kind of tasks uh that are common across
users in every industry every role every
region and it's really great that you
know we can help here um and uh allow
our partner Community to then focus on
the industry specifics and uh finally as
you know copilot is getting better over
time uh We've no doubt that it will help
workers uh achieve more and eliminate uh
these tedious tasks and allow people to
focus on what really matters which you
know at the end of the day is uh running
their
business so for today's talk uh let's
jump straight into what co-pilot can do
for you uh we'll start with a co-pilot
demo or we cover uh what chat is good
for and show you some tips on how to get
the most out of it then we'll we'll talk
a little bit about the preview what does
it actually mean um how do the how how
does co-pilot answer questions and how
can you administrate this new capability
and finally we'll wrap up by sharing all
the details you need to go and try it
out yourself uh and uh you can go and
play with chat so let's kick off the
demo over to you Mac shall we do that
Sam let's dive in let's take a look at
what this looks like here I am in
business Central and I can chat with
co-pilot at any time no matter where I
am inside the application and to start
chat I will find the co-pilot icon in
the app bar up
top and the chat pane slides in and I
have this welcoming message from
co-pilot uh and you can see how this is
seamlessly integrated into the business
Central uh experience on the web client
um and it sits alongside my data so it
helps me it's always there alongside my
my work um here the welcoming message
also explains the kind of tasks that
co-pilot can help with it can help find
records from the database it can help
explain Concepts and help me understand
things in business Central but also
guide me on how to complete those tasks
how to complete those business processes
now these are three nice examples here
to get me started but I've actually got
so many more here in the what we call
the prompt guide um here are different
examples which really just give me a
sense of you know Inspire Me Maybe to
how I could communicate and chat with
co-pilot um different ways of writing my
my questions my prompts uh covering
these different abilities that it has um
here I have for example let's pick this
one is there a keyboard shortcut um and
you can see how it it's actually like a
template where I get to fill in the
blanks so let's see what am I interested
in is there a keyboard shortcut for
accessing all actions on my
page and now I've sent that first chat
chat message to copilot copilot is
digging up information from our business
Central online documentation as well and
will bring me an answer promptly that I
can use so here you can see how co-pilot
has given me an answer to my question
and it suggest to use the ALT key to
display keytips um which are the letters
on the screen that appear right now and
I can I can proceed with working with my
action bar I'll use the letter G I'll
use the letter D wow so I've just
learned a new skill thanks to co-pilot
here it's helped me figure that out now
there's of course a lot more you can do
with chatting with co-pilot here so
think about all the different times
during your workday where you get this
Interruption somebody comes along and
asks you a question that's got nothing
to do with the task you're currently
working on like setting up my general
ledger and think about how distracting
that is and co-pilot is here to help so
do we have any chair in stock under 300
bucks so that's my question it's very
unrelated to the task I'm doing right
now in business Central but while
co-pilot finds the answer I can continue
working I can continue setting up my
general ledger in this case which happen
to be my task I can fully interact with
the business Central client uh and all
the different pages I can continue
working while co-pilot does the hard
work for
me and you can see copilot has now come
back with an answer it's returned three
records and in fact these are presented
in uh the kind of way that you're
already familiar with as tiles where we
have a thumbnail image of that record we
have some of the important fields and
you know this from the web client you've
seen it on your mobile app you've seen
it as you share records in teams as well
and these are of course interactive as
well so I can click on any one of these
such as the London chair here and now to
help my coworker who had this question I
can simply share that to
teams so this information that co-pilot
retrieves is also
interactive now you'll find that as you
have conversations with co-pilot uh in
that chat pane uh over time the
conversation can get quite long uh you
might also want to um sort of help pilot
by indicating that you're starting a new
topic of conversation so for here I can
clear the chat pain and start a fresh
all over again well okay let's now try a
completely different question to
co-pilot I'm going to ask for show me
the latest invoices for
Alpine now those of you who are familiar
with u business Central's demo data will
know that Alpine is in fact a customer
Alpine Ski house but here notice how I
formulated the question in a very loose
manner I didn't spend specified a full
customer name I didn't even specify if
this was meant to be purchase or sales
invoices um so even though we can
formulate questions to co-pilot in this
loose way co-pilot still figures it out
and here it's come back in fact with
three invoices from the posted sales
invoice list for Alpine Ski House and
again this is presented in the same way
as tiles that you can interact with but
you can also check um again what filters
did copilot apply to actually come to
that conclusion I'm in the posted sales
invoices list I can see the filter it's
applied here I can see the Sorting on
due date that's been applied that's how
it got to the an answer this helps me
verify uh that it has used the right
correct logic to get to an answer but
because this is a conversation I can
also ask follow-up questions to co-pilot
for
example which of these are
unpaid now here I'm clearly referring to
the invoices that already found in this
list so when I'm asking about it being
unpaid about it being um still open uh
it is referring to you know the latest
invoices that were found there it's a
reference back to that but because
copilot understands the history of my
conversation it's able to help me with
getting to an
answer so again co-pilot can uh help me
go back and forth in conversation here
uh help me narrow down to find precisely
the data the records that I'm looking
for over to you Sam thanks Mike uh so as
Mike just showed us uh co-pilot
effectively has two capabilities uh one
is to quickly find relevant records and
uh the other is to look up uh business
processes and clarifying that kind of
thing uh so I I'll talk a little bit
about uh each in in some more detail um
so yeah co-pilot is great at quickly
finding uh relevant records and in
particularly these kind of onetime
queries where it's not really worth
having you know a page view saved for
for your kind of answer
uh so for example here you can see I'm
uh looking up uh uh to show me the sales
orders for a datum uh by the amount and
um exactly I get these uh three records
shown here and then I can navigate to
the full page uh with the filters
applied and then look at all the the
relevant um sales
orders so uh to get the most out of it
it really helps to understand what copal
is actually doing uh to find these
records and essentially it looks up uh
the relevant page uh for your ask and
then tries to construct a filter on this
page uh to answer the question and then
looking at the records uh from that
resulting set so keeping this in mind
when you're formulating your questions
for Coby um specifying the type of page
that you know uh you want to look at
helps um what kind of data you want to
find at the page and kind any kind of
sorting that you you are interested in
are all good pieces of information to
provide and then co-pilot always uh
respond with a link to the page or an
explanation of what kind of filtering
was done to explain the the results uh
in in the
answer and just another thing to keep in
mind is that while copal is in preview
uh it's not aware of the the context of
your current page so if you're talking
about information you see on the current
page it's good to include this
information in your chat message as
well um secondly again as Mike showed uh
this is a conversation so you can always
go ahead and ask clarifying questions um
so for example here I asked what is the
highest amount and sure I could have
opened up the the sales holders page
myself and changed the Sorting uh but I
could have also just stayed in the chat
Pane and uh yeah asked the question got
the result and here I get a citation as
well which will take me straight to the
record then uh for the next capability
uh co-pilot can search the official uh
business Central uh document mentation
to answer product related questions uh
it's worth noting that it will go
directly to the documentation and it
doesn't perform like a general web
search through Bing uh so you can be
sure that the results that it gets back
is always uh coming from the
documentation so in this case again you
can see uh I'm asking about some
particular terminology and uh what we
have found here is a documentation uh
link that talks about the actual process
um and um within that documentation page
it talks about the inverse of my
question um and so from that we can we
can uh get an
answer um which is good um and then the
user can now go to the documentation
page to read more or um you know uh you
rather than reading all the
documentation you can go and ask a
follow-up question so for example how
can I do that and then um uh the chat
will respond with some steps uh if if
they are provided within the
documentation so this is a really nice
like complement to any kind of
onboarding or training process that you
may have in place and really helps with
uh learning how to use uh business
Central uh so to reiterate kind of the
results you get back all come from the
business Central documentation they're
all grounded on content in there so for
example you might ask a question which
isn't actually covered in the
documentation and in this case rather
than trying to fabricate some answer it
will say that there's no information in
the documentation on how to do this uh
but here are some relevant uh pages in
the documentation uh you can go and read
up on uh to hopefully uh learn more
about the the process you're asking um
so yeah I hope this helps everyone uh
writing more effective questions for
co-pilot and I'll hand back to Mike who
can uh maybe tell us a bit about the
availability of the preview thanks Sam
so because this is in preview there's a
few key points we really want you to
understand first of all co-pilot in
business Central in general is available
exclusively for business Central online
which means you won't find it on
business Central deployed to on premises
or private Cloud um and this has been
released for uh 2024 release Wave 1 um
that means you'll find it with major
update
24.0 or later uh roll out starts with
our us customers uh and then throughout
the release wave over a number of weeks
and months we'll make that available to
other uh regions as as well with the
exception of Canada where chat will not
be available to Canadian customers uh
due to compliance reasons um finally
chat is available in English only while
in preview uh and one of the common
questions we also get about uh copilot
which applies very much to chat as well
is well how much does this cost uh is
there a minimum number of seats required
to use this the answer is very simple at
this stage chat and in fact co-pilot in
business Central in general is available
with business Central licenses at no
additional
cost here's a few more points that are
really good for you to understand so
that you can plan your approach so first
of all extensibility uh you cannot
extend modify override or add new
capabilities to chat um we certainly
aspire to unlock this in the future but
for now in preview um this is not
possible so keep that in mind when you
listen to our some of our other sessions
where we talk about the developer tools
for co-pilot and business Central those
let you do other things with generative
AI um chat itself is not extensible uh
secondly um and this is where you know
all hope is not lost uh basically chat
can find records in your custom objects
your tables and your list Pages uh so if
you for example have added the the
vehicles list page where you got a whole
bunch of Records you'll still be able to
uh get to that information as well using
co-pilot um so whether that's a
customization whether that's an add-on
solution it just works there's no
additional effort needed uh from our
partner Community for their objects to
also work with
chat and because answers come from
Microsoft's online documentation hosted
on Microsoft learn uh this also means
that if you ask questions about custom
Fields custom processes in business
Central anything very specific that you
do in your company that may be captured
in other knowledge sources co-pilot at
at this stage will not be able to answer
those kind of those kind of questions um
it does draw from end user documentation
from Microsoft the administrator
documentation the developer docs as well
but it also won't generate any code or
display any Al code uh in the chat
Paine um the last thing that's also good
to know and that's a subtle point is uh
that you know if if you've asked
co-pilot to find some data it can only
find data based on the filters and the
fields that are available so if you ask
for something that goes beyond that of
course you will not be able to return uh
any
results all right well let's talk about
trust next yeah thanks back so we
designed this feature uh from the ground
up uh with Microsoft's values and uh
responsible AI standards um and what
this really is is that your data is your
data uh you know and a story um your
data is not used to train the foundation
AI models and your data is protected by
the most comprehensive Enterprise
compliance and security controls so what
does that really mean it means that uh
for example the queries you type in
co-pilot chat uh will uh respect the
users permission uh sets that have been
assigned you know they're not going to
be able to ask questions uh for things
that that the users don't have access to
and finally uh you know copat is built
on Microsoft's responsible AI standards
of fairness reliability safety
inclusiveness transparency and
accountability um
so you know these aren't just words we
really take the time to go through each
feature and design for harnessing AI
safety from the ground up and we apply
what we call the responsible AI
practices um you know we know that the
AI is sometimes incorrect so we've taken
uh extra me measures to ensure that the
answers copilot provides uh answer to a
high degree of accuracy uh for example
it will always provide a clear
explanation of how the answer was found
it will provide links and citations to
its sources and finally we apply what we
call grounding checks uh to avoid
Fabrications from the model uh before
presenting uh the answer in
chat now if you're a partner who's eager
to demo this to your customers or simply
get Hands-On and try it yourself here's
a few tips just for you uh so first of
all um we always recommend for demos
that you use CDX uh customer digital
experiences um just go to aka.ms CDX uh
sign in with your partner identity uh as
a partner you already have access to
this once you're in there you can
quickly spin up a new tenant uh
basically you get an admin and a whole
set of test user uh credentials um and
we suggest you always create a new
browser profile you sign up for business
Central in there using that admin
account um and then you've got access to
business Central uh and um since you
know chat is being rolled out gradually
to different uh geographies um it's
probably easiest in the beginning uh to
provision a US environment and that will
give you chat and there's really no
further configuration you need to go
through you are ready to start using
co-pilot in that situation but if you um
if you're in there and you can't find
co-pilot here's just a couple of small
tips for you uh things that you can
check so first go and check the co-pilot
ni capabilities page this is a single
and simple space that we've created for
admins uh that gives transparency into
these are the generative AI features
available in this particular environment
if you don't see chat in there uh it
hasn't been made available yet uh to
your particular environment um here make
sure that uh you know chat is active uh
and on some environments you will also
see uh a switch um that you can turn on
to give consent to uh con business
Central contacting Azure open AI service
that may be in a different region and
what this means is that for some of our
regions depending on where you're
located depending on on that uh uh that
environment um data may need to be sent
to Azure openi service that is outside
of your Geographic boundary and that is
something admins need to consent to to
use this um there's a few other things
you can do um you know make sure that uh
your language is set to English in my
settings uh make sure you're on you've
been updated to version 24
um and essentially you know those are
all the things that you need to do to
check if you don't see co-pilot over
there if you don't have chat with
co-pilot just yet you may just need to
wait a little bit longer until we roll
it out uh to that region okay so um just
a last Quick demo of the day so business
Central is of course a very extremely
rich and advanced business application
there's many things to learn to master
including uh how to use each specific
field now co-pilot is your AI assistant
to help you through that process as well
to explain feels in business Central so
I'd like to next show you this demo
where we get help from
co-pilot so let's imagine I'm still
performing this task of reconfiguring my
general ledgers and there's a couple of
fields here I'm not quite sure what they
represent there's allow posting from
there's deferral posting U we've made it
really easy with a single click to be
able to get more information from
co-pilot when the Tool tip just doesn't
have enough now typically uh if I
couldn't ask co-pilot right here what I
do is I'd go and search Microsoft's
documentation myself do a number of
queries there to and Search terms to
figure out what I'm looking for but here
I simply ask co-pilot what is the allow
posting from field what is that all
about as you can see um you know by that
one click uh it's added a chat message
in there uh to co-pilot and co-pilot
goes off and figures out the answer and
again I can have follow-up questions to
this as well so H uh how is this
different to deferral
posting so as I work in business Central
uh I've got co-pilot as my assistant by
my side helping me understand these
Concepts and we've made it super easy
with a single click just to be able to
get to that and this is because uh
business Central in general has tool
tips on fields uh has documentation
which documents the and explains you
know business processes and pages but
there isn't specific you know field
level uh help documentation it's sort of
spread out across different prices so
here co-pilot helps bring it all in into
one space where I don't even need to
leave the application I can easily get
to that information and work uh in
business Central that's really cool Mike
I think that's such a a seamless way of
learning more about business Central and
I really like that you can just go and
ask follow-up questions uh in a
conversational format uh once the the
chat pane is open so now you should know
how to get and try out copilot for
yourself
uh and we'd love to get your feedback
and uh help us improve by liking or
disliking the responses that you see in
the chat Pane and this can me done the
the thumbs up or the thumbs down uh the
your feedback is very important to us
because it helps give a signal on areas
uh where we can improve and I'll
reiterate you know that like we said
earlier uh that we will not use the data
for training the foundation model models
so back to you m thanks Sam well I think
we can wrap things up now so there's so
much more C- in 2024 release wave 1 uh
check out these recommended sessions
where we cover how co-pilots help helps
people use their own words to uh fill
out sales lines quickly and effectively
or to uh create analytical views of
their data uh and get to insights a lot
faster but also how co-pilot helps
reduce the tedious tasks such as
matching electronic uh documents with
your purchase
orders now if you're looking for uh more
resources about co-pilot and about chat
specifically for start if you haven't
seen it we definitely recommend a
two-minute video that you can show your
customers as well about chat and roughly
how it works uh if you need more
detailed information uh we encourage
Partners to uh engage with us on Viva
engage for example have a discussion
with the product team share your
feedback and ideas there as well uh or
dig into our documentation for even more
answers and examples of how you can work
with
chat uh of course if you want to extend
co-pilot as I said earlier uh uh you
cannot extend chat today but you can
also build other generative AI
experiences in business Central check
out our toolkit for that one and finally
if you're new to business Central uh
there's plenty more resources for you
everything from connecting to the
engineering team to uh contributing your
ideas your code uh or simply learning
new
skills so we'll end here with a big
thank you thank you not just for
listening in but also for trying out
chat with co-pilot and sharing your
feedback your feedback is tremendously
important for us to improve co-pilot
over time uh we think the potential with
AI is tremendous in transforming how our
customers do business and interact with
business applications but it's all about
channeling that power towards uh how you
our partners and our customers apply
that AI put it to work every single day
to help you be more productive uh so
we're looking forward to your feedback
your reactions your ideas as well uh
send them our way we're eager to engage
and on behalf of the team thanks a lot
and thanks for joining
us